- Where have you been?
- Hunting and gathering.
The victim's name is Timothy Hartley.
He was killed sometime last night.
He was shot in the chest,
and then his throat was slit.
Charming.
His I.D. says he's from about a hundred
miles away from here... Hillsborough.
No sign of what he was doing up here.
Sheriff says Hartley's car's down the road.
- I'll check it out.
- All right.
- You tell him?
- Tell him what?
- Coroner's office sent Steiner.
- Dr. Steiner?
And we all know how much you like
to make fun of Dr. Steiner so don't, okay?
I don't know what you're talking about.
- No humoring yourself at his expense.
- Is he that way?
Top of the morning to you, Steiner.
- You're looking trim.
- Jane.
Curiously considerate killer.
Slit his throat after the shots
to put him out of his misery.
- Three steps back, please.
- What?
Please maintain a distance
of at least three steps from the body.
- Why?
- Because this body is a no-Jane zone.
It will not be a playground for you.
You will not touch it or sniff it
or place playing cards on it
or borrow it for an interrogation.
If you do, a deputy will remove you.
Clear?
That's a little harsh, no?
You have driven me
to desperate measures.
Well, I'm nothing if I'm not respectful
of my fellow crime-fighters.
But I can see everything I need to
from here anyway.
Really? W...
What exactly do you see?
He's in money, but not a banker
something more aggressive...
stocks or such, social drinker
increased his intake lately
so under some pressure.
A registered, uh, independent, though
always votes republican
and as much money as he has,
his wife has more.
- Ridiculous.
- He chose the tasteless tasseled loafers.
She bought the opal-enlaced
sterling silver cuff links.
Guesses.
You might as well say he's going
to meet a tall, dark stranger.
That's very unlikely, doctor.
He's dead.
And by the way, it looks like there's
something in his left-front pant pocket.
You are about to think,
"What the hell"? "How did Jane..."
"Do that?"
How did you do that?
"There are more things in
heaven and earth, Horatio"
"than dreamt of in your philosophy."
Okay. You planned ahead.
You asked one of the sheriff's
deputies to call you
the next time Steiner was on a case
and then you asked them
to plant the note.
That is an absurd theory.
You know this means another apology
at the coroner's office.
- No, it doesn't.
- Yes, it does.
- Steiner loves the attention.
- Lisbon.
What happened?
Where are they?
It was a robbery.
Two guys in a pickup pulled
the coroner's van over and held it up.
What'd they steal?
- Get this... your vic's body.
- Hartley's corpse?
That's right. Steiner tried to stop them
believe it or not.
- Dr. Steiner.
- Agent Lisbon.
It's not as bad as it looks.
Go get yourself checked out
and then come talk to us.
Jane, was this you?
- W...
- Another trick?
Jane had nothing to do
with this, nothing at all.
- You didn't, did you?
- Of course not.
- Swear on your life?
- On your life, even.
- Damn it. Who steals a body?
- Interesting though.
The pickup was... pulled over.
There were two men,
apparently working on the engine.
They flagged us down
for help, we thought,
and then they pulled out guns.
Can you describe them?
They were both white
a little under 6 feet, I think.
I can't really say much more.
They wore hooded s...
jackets and sunglasses.
One went to the van
and dragged the body bag out.
The one guarding us
went to help him, and...
That's when I...
Intervened.
Foolish.
For once, I agree with you.
They put the body into the truck
and they... they took off.
- Why would anyone do this?
- We don't know yet. It's early.
I have to take this. I'm sorry.
Thank you for your time, Dr. Steiner.
Of course.
Lisbon. Thanks for getting back to me.
- Bye again, Mr. Jane.
- It wasn't your fault.
Excuse me?
They had guns.
Big, scary guns.
There's nothing you could do.
The body is my responsibility,
my reason for being here.
Now I have no reason
or responsibility.
There's nothing for me to do.
I don't expect you to understand why that
feels like failure to me but it does.
- Want a cup of tea?
- I don't think so.
Suit yourself.
I like the chapel in Yountville.
It's just a long way
for the guests to go.
What did you find out
about Vandermeer State Park?
I love that place.
I see.
Well, I guess we'll just keep looking.
I love you Craig. Bye.
Vandermeer State Park...
Beautiful for a wedding.
I've hiked there.
There's an old quaker meeting house.
Oh, it would be perfect.
But I guess they don't allow weddings.
It's too hard on the ground vegetation.
What do we have on Hartley?
Jane was right.
He was in finance.
Ran a hedge fund called
the H.V. Wilder Fund.
But his wife's family has the real money.
- Name's Cook.
- The Cooks?
Yeah, I guess.
Wife's name is Peregrine.
I'll deal with the family.
You go and talk to the people
he worked with.
Anything on the missing corpse?
Forensics found no usable prints
on the van
and nothing from the tire tracks
at the scene.
Why steal a dead body?
What can they use it for?
Got me.
Go and have another talk with the two guys
that were with Steiner.
Get any details
on the thieves or the truck.
Van Pelt, look for any similar crimes
bodies that were stolen from hospitals
- ambulances, anything.
- Good luck with the Cooks.
Yeah, nothing like telling people
their loved ones are dead
and oh, by the way,
we lost the corpse.
None of this makes any sense.
The last time I-I spoke to Tim
he was telling me some stupid joke
he heard at work
happy as ever.
Who's responsible, agent?
My son-in-law didn't just disappear.
Someone is accountable. Who?
Ma'am, we don't know yet.
We're doing the best we can.
- Not good enough.
- Mother!
My dear, when they tell you
they're doing their very best
- that's exactly what they aren't doing.
- Hell of a place you've got here.
- Where'd you get the money for it?
- Excuse me?
The moolah. The scratch.
The shekels. The dollarinis.
What does that have
to do with anything?
Obviously something
you're embarrassed about.
- Sugar beets.
- Sugar beets?
- My, uh, my grandfather grew them.
- I love sugar beets.
There's no shame in sugar beets, Elspeth.
Mrs. Hartley, we found your husband's body
a hundred miles from here.
- Any idea what he was doing out there?
- No, none at all.
Was there anything out of the ordinary
going on in his life? Troubles at work?
- Changes in his schedule?
- No.
We started...
Talking about having...
A family...
A while back.
There, there, dear.
If there are no more questions...
You didn't like your
son-in-law, did you?
You found him vulgar
despite his highfalutin job.
And you... you're frightened.
The body's disappearance alarms you
in a very specific way. What is that?
Harrison, please show our visitors out.
Thank you. I'm good.
"Oh, God."
Why do these things happen?
How long have you and
Mr. Hartley been partners?
Oh, uh, five years or so.
We were both interested in a fund
that offered slightly esoteric
financial instruments.
- A hedge fund.
- What we do is pretty complicated.
I don't want to bore you
with the details.
As I understand it, you rely on a strategy
that exploits mean reversion tendencies
of crosscurrent far forward rates.
Is that right?
Yes.
What did Mr. Hartley
do for the fund?
Built it.
Designed the strategy.
Certifiable genius.
The best.
A fund like yours can lose
people a lot of money.
- Any angry investors?
- No, no, no.
Recently, we've had excellent returns.
What about work?
Did Hartley have problems here?
"Loved" is the word.
- How about trouble at home?
- No. Tim adored Peregrine.
He... he... he was a boy scout.
He would never play around,
wouldn't even think of it.
- He's a straight... straight arrow.
- I see.
The straightest.
So nothing new from
the guys with Steiner
but it wasn't an entirely
wasted journey. I got scones.
I found something.
Three other corpses have been stolen
from vehicles leaving crime scenes
over the past six months.
- Who caught the cases?
- We did.
- Rigsby.
- O'Laughlin.
Why is the FBI on this?
It's interstate. One of the corpses
was taken in Nevada.
- You guys have a theory?
- Yeah.
We think the bodies are
being sold at tissue banks.
Tissue banks?
They harvest bone and tissue
from the corpses
then sell them to
medical supply houses.
You're supposed to get permission
from the family to sell the corpse
but these guys are skipping that part.
And tissue banks are regulated
so more likely the thieves are
working with the Funeral Home.
They provide the
bodies to tissue banks.
I put together a list of
Funeral Homes in the area.
- We can start with that.
- Great, yeah.
Hey, Rigsby, my boss
asked me to come
you know, since I've worked
with CBI before.
I'm not trying to get in your face
is all I'm saying.
Didn't think you were.
- Okay, good.
- Okay.
Dr. Steiner, I presume.
What brings you back?
Good news, actually.
A small amount of blood
was recovered
from the dirt under the body
at the crime scene.
It contains two distinct
DNA signatures.
The killer got cut, too.
Yes, probably while using
a knife on the victim.
There's not enough blood for an I.D.
but there could be more on the corpse.
Interesting. Why did you come and tell
me that in person instead of calling?
I would like to assist in some
small way, if that's all right.
Okay. Let's go get
you a gun, shall we?
Kidding. Welcome. Come on.
Look sharp, Lisbon.
We have a visitor.
- Dr. Steiner? Can I help you?
- Well, actually, I...
Steiner's gonna be
joining us for a while.
Um... okay.
- What is all this mess?
- It's Hartley's calendar and phone records.
We're making a list of people he saw
before he died.
Meh. Clerical work.
We need to figure out what the big secret is.
- What big secret?
- Yeah, what big secret?
The big, weird secret that the widow
and the partner
and everyone won't tell us about
because it's too shameful to mention.
It's funny you should mention that.
He... he did have an appointment
every week with no description.
Thursdays, 2:15 to 3:30.
No name, no address.
- Interesting.
- Clerical work, huh?
- Touché.
- If I may
his car's GPS
might have an address.
- Yes, it might.
- See? Useful already.
2729 Hillview Avenue.
This is the address
in Hartley's GPS.
Okay, what's the game with Steiner?
- No game.
- What's he doing here, then?
What are any of us doing here?
We don't bring guests
on investigations.
Maybe we should.
A different mystery sleuth for each case.
Well, if this is some gag
you're pulling...
It's not. He asked if he could
come along and I said he could.
All right? That's it.
We're building bridges,
mending fences...
Okay.
Planting seeds...
- Laying foundations.
- Okay.
It's a medical building, G.P.'s,
dentists, but mostly shrinks.
How do you know who to talk to?
Any calls on his phone records
to this address?
No, but we can check his bank records
for payments.
Oh, we'd need a warrant for that.
I'd rather just start knocking on doors.
Then we're gonna need more people.
You'll have to clear that with admin.
Okay, everybody, outside! Outside!
Come on! It's not a drill!
- Oh, God, Jane. Why did you do that?
- Hustle it out. Hustle it out.
That's the way.
All of you.
Hello, ladies and gentlemen. My name
is Patrick Jane. I'm with the CBI.
We are looking for the doctor
who treated Timothy Hartley.
I know you have a doctor/patient
confidentiality thing.
Let's not worry about that right now.
Would Timothy Hartley's doctor
please raise his or her hand?
Raise it on up.
I know it's one of you.
Maybe to your right
maybe to your left.
Up, up, up, up with your hand.
Bring it up.
Okay, so no one has raised their hand.
That doesn't matter
because I know that you, ma'am
are the person who we seek.
Please come forward.
Everyone else, thank you,
and back to your quackery.
- What's your name, ma'am?
- Dr. Wendelyne McCormick.
And I won't discuss my patients
or the fact that someone is my patient.
We're investigating the murder
of Timothy Hartley.
He was killed last night.
Oh, God.
All right.
How did you know it was me?
Everyone else was looking
around to see who it was
but you weren't, because you knew.
Great. The fire department.
I'll go talk to 'em.
Tim had been in therapy
for about four months.
He'd had a traumatizing experience
that he wanted to work through.
What kind of an experience?
Agent, can I get some assurance
of discretion from you?
It's a sensitive matter
to the people around him.
- We can't promise anything.
- Very well.
About five months ago
he had an abduction experience.
Excuse me?
He believed he was abducted
by extraterrestrial beings...
Taken to their ship, examined
and released.
Kidnapped by aliens.
Cool.
"I was being lifted by
the light, up and away."
"I-I couldn't... couldn't do anything."
"I was just being...
taken right to the ship."
It happened when Hartley was driving home
from a trip to Reno.
We found a couple of these videos
on his personal laptop
some kind of diary of the event.
"And once on the ship, there were..."
"There were beings all around me"
"small..."
"just ash gray."
"And there were a little taller ones too...
they're the same color."
"They were leaders, I think."
"It just all feels so..."
"It feels so concrete"
"so real."
- Crazy.
- He sounds sincere to me.
- Sincerely cuckoo.
- I don't see any sign he's lying.
It could be a dream that he experienced
during a hypnagogic state.
That would make it true for him
but not objectively real.
Exactly. I agree with him completely.
Thousands of people say
it's happened to them.
They can't all be crazy or lying.
I'm just saying you
should keep an open mind.
- You can't prove there aren't aliens.
- That's true.
Okay, the point is the wife
had to have known about this.
- We need to talk to her again.
- Yeah.
Where are we with the body hunt?
We've identified eight funeral parlors
that had extensive legitimate dealings
with tissue banks.
We're gonna start with them.
We're splitting the interviews
with O'Laughlin.
- All right, let me know what you find.
- Okay.
Watch the skies, Grace.
Tim told me as soon as it happened.
He said he met them
in a field outside Auburn.
Where we found his body?
He kept going back.
He couldn't tell me why.
I mean, he knew it wasn't rational.
Why didn't you tell us this before?
I got a call from Art Vella
Tim's partner.
He told me not to mention it, begged me.
He said it would be devastating
for the business.
You believed your husband's
story, didn't you?
That's why you were so scared
when the body disappeared.
- You thought the aliens took him.
- Okay, okay.
Listen to me.
My husband wasn't crazy.
Okay?
He wouldn't lie to me
about something like that.
Rubbish! When someone tells you
something contrary to fact
they are lying, full stop.
Don't start, mother.
Agents, my son-in-law was drunk
or drug-addled or both.
As for this tabloid trash
about men from Mars...
- Ladies.
- How can you say that?
- Ridiculous. Just ridiculous!
- This is so like you, mother...
I've never heard such twaddle
in my life...
- so closed off and close-minded.
- And he said it with a straight face.
- You honestly think...
- Ladies. Ladies, that's enough.
Wait. What are you looking for?
Ah, yes.
You're a scotch man, right?
Uh, yes. I...
Oh, no, no. I-I shouldn't.
You really should.
Cheers.
You know, don't you?
- Excuse me?
- You know that I'm sick.
Why would Patrick Jane, of all people
invite me to a fancy house
and put a first-rate scotch
in my hand if he didn't know?
- You've lost some weight... 8 pounds.
- Yes.
Your face is looking drawn.
You're taking some
powerful medication.
I can see it in the
pallor of your skin.
Yes.
I'm dying.
I have a month...
Most likely, maybe less.
I'm sorry.
Thank you for the distraction.
Well, it's always good to...
Keep busy.
There's probably some, uh,
Havana cigars in that box there.
No. No, no. I...
I couldn't.
Could I?
Well, you're right.
This is a good cigar.
The only other time
that I had been in a room like this
was to examine a man
who died accidentally
in the middle of an autoerotic ritual.
Well, I bet he died
with a smile on his face.
Excuse me.
Can I help you?
Just leaving Harrison.
Why did you tell Peregrine
Hartley to lie to us, sir?
I didn't tell her to lie.
I asked Peregrine not to raise
certain relevant information.
Why'd you do that?
Tim was the brain.
I handled clients, administration.
It's all about confidence.
If the investors hear about
alien probes and whatnot
confidence goes right out the window.
Then I assume you asked him
not to talk about this.
Constantly.
But Mr. Hartley was growing certain
his experiences were real.
He must've wanted to talk about it.
- We had some arguments about it.
- Bad arguments?
I didn't kill Tim because he wanted
to go public with his cuckoo story.
You need to talk to that UFO
fruitcake that Tim met.
They're friends about a week
and then Tim wanted nothing more
to do with him.
I think he was trying to
squeeze some money out of Tim.
What's his name?
Kirk. Can you believe that?
Newsom Kirk.
Is there any way
you can keep this quiet?
- I doubt it.
- $2.8 billion in assets.
We're going down
because my partner
thought he was
kidnapped by little green men.
- Gray.
- What?
The little men. They're gray.
- Thanks for your time. Appreciate it.
- Thank you, bye.
Two down, two to go.
Wanna grab some food?
Oh, there's an errand I wanna run.
Give me half an hour. I'll catch up.
- Where you going? I'll take you.
- You don't need to do that.
- Oh, come on. How far is it?
- It's a little ways. It's okay.
- It's a wedding thing.
- Oh, I see.
Why don't I drop you off?
I'll grab something to eat
and then stay in the car, okay?
Sure.
Hello.
"Hey, it's O'Laughlin. I tried Grace.
She didn't answer."
- She's busy.
- "Where are you? I've got something."
Gary Wineman, funeral director.
Mentioned tissue banks,
and he got very nervous.
Mr. Wineman, these are
my colleagues from CBI
Agents Rigsby and Van Pelt.
Did agent O'Laughlin mention
what this was about, sir?
Uh, some... bodies have been stolen
that might have gone to a tissue bank?
No, that's the FBI's investigation.
We're investigating a murder.
You didn't say anything about that.
- I certainly don't know anything about it.
- Well, I hope so, sir.
A case like this, anyone connected to it...
Even remotely connected... is in big trouble.
Best thing to protect yourself...
be very clear about what you know
and what you've done.
Oh, God. Uh, look...
We...
My wife had a baby girl
and we needed a little extra cash
so I started selling bodies
to tissue banks...
All... all legitimate.
I got permission every time.
But the banks always want more bodies
and my wife got pregnant again.
- Look, who came to you?
- My cousin. Not a good person.
He said that if we split the fee
he could provide bodies,
no permission necessary.
All I have to do was dummy up paperwork
giving them false names.
Did he bring you a corpse today?
No, no, no, no.
But I... he has done this before
with other funeral homes.
His name is Owen Melling.
- I-I-I had no I...
- Where is he now, sir?
Melling's done time for assault,
armed robbery and truck hijacking.
Did the truck jobs with a buddy
named Jim Matthews.
Both are on parole. Melling owes 15 years,
Matthew has 12.
And they know if they get picked up
they're violated back in.
It's good times.
Owen Melling?
CBI.
We need to talk to you about
a robbery this morning.
Just wanna get some facts straight.
Come down to the office,
and we can explain.
Jim. Cops.
- Jim Matthews?
- Yeah. What's up?
Says it's about some
robbery this morning.
So what?
- We were right here.
- That's right.
Been here all day.
Yeah, well, we still
need to talk to you.
Now get your hands
out of your pocket.
- Hands where we can see 'em.
- You heard him. Now.
Don't hassle my boy!
He ain't done nothin'!
Put the weapon down, ma'am.
You just wanna make more trouble for him.
I won't have it.
We just wanna talk to your son.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Just put down the gun, ma'am.
Please!
Gun!
O'Llaughlin, Grace is in trouble.
Cover me.
O'Laughlin!
Grace, get down!
On the ground! Face down! Now!
Get on the ground!
- How'd the interview with Matthews go?
- Didn't. He asked for a lawyer.
- What'd you find in Melling's house?
- No sign of Hartley's body.
Forensics is checking
the pickup for DNA.
I got something.
According to his cell phone records
Melling made a call yesterday
to a Wellview Funeral Home.
Could be where they dropped off
Hartley's body.
Get Steiner and go and check it out.
If the body's there he's the one to I.D. it.
Sure.
Tracked down an address
for Newsom Kirk
the guy Hartley had
a falling-out with.
He runs an organization for abductees
called the Fourth Kind Foundation.
Office is downtown.
- Does he have a sheet?
- Running it now.
We'll go talk to him.
Call if anything pops. Okay.
Newsom Kirk, I'm agent Lisbon.
- This is agent Cho. We're with the CBI.
Yes. So sad about Hartley. Welcome.
Welcome.
Agent Cho, you... you've...
you've been, haven't you?
Excuse me?
Up. Taken, with them.
No.
Well, I'm getting a...
I'm getting a definite sense.
It sometimes takes a person years
to realize they've had the experience.
- Timothy Hartley.
- Of course. Sorry.
You met him through
the foundation, right?
Yeah. We're here to serve abductees
help them come to terms
with their experience.
Spread the word.
Tim wanted to talk about
what he'd been going through.
He asked us to keep it in confidence,
and... and we did.
And that's all you did...
talk about his experience?
No. As a matter of fact,
Tim had a lot of money.
And frankly, we... we need money
we had... we had several
quite serious discussions
about funding this... this place.
As a child...
Did... did you have, um, dreams
where you were floating
through the house
as though pulled by an unseen force?
No.
Uh, we heard that the, uh, two of you
had some sort of a falling-out?
He decided that he wanted to
start his own foundation.
- Uh, his right, I say.
- It never got angry?
No, no. Uh, if you're looking
for someone Tim had a fight with
you should talk to that shrink of his.
Uh, McCormick.
She wanted to write a book about him.
He said no. She was angry.
- Okay.
- Boss, from Rigsby.
Mr. Newsom, is your real name
Garrett Rosten?
And did you spend a year in Chino prison
for fraud?
Because your arrest record
says you did.
In my previous life,
I was Garrett Rosten, yes.
Mr. Hartley seems like the kind of guy
who would research somebody
If he was considering funding them.
- Did he find out about this?
- I never hid Garrett.
- I'm simply a different person now.
- Not that different.
There's a bench warrant out for your arrest
for kiting checks.
- We're gonna have to take you in.
- Turn around, please.
It's... it's okay. It's...
Just a misunderstanding.
Hey, agent.
The important thing is that you
take a look inside yourself
and start questioning
those experiences...
that you can't explain.
Never happened.
I believe you.
Wake up.
Newsom Kirk posted bail.
He's gonna be gone in an hour.
Just in time for the
6:10 to Alpha Centauri.
He was right about
Hartley's psychiatrist.
She did propose a book,
but she withdrew it.
- So she had motive.
- Kinda.
- Who do you think did it?
- Jabba the Hutt.
- Seriously.
- Ming the merciless.
- Okay.
- Alf?
When the aliens do come,
I hope they eat you.
- Lisbon.
- Theresa, Brenda Shettrick.
A local news crew is about
to interview Dr. Steiner
about the Hartley case.
Just thought you'd like to know.
He's supposed to be looking
for Hartley's body.
No, he's here.
"What interview?"
Some background on tissue banks
and the corpse trade.
There's a lot of interest.
He offered to do it.
- "You didn't know anything?"
- I'll be right there.
Bye, Lisbon.
The legitimate trade in tissue
is a valuable source of biological material
for medical use.
Unfortunately, this illegal trade
has halted the investigation
- into the death of Timothy Hartley.
- How's that?
Well, I-I just came
from a funeral home
where we had hoped to find
Mr. Hartley's body
and it's... it's... it's not there.
The thieves have hidden it somewhere.
And there is crucial
evidence... blood evidence...
on Mr. Hartley's body
that will identify the killers.
- Brenda.
- If we don't find that evidence...
- Now.
- Guys, that's it. Thanks very much.
Did I do something wrong?
We don't talk to the press
about evidence.
It kinda tells the killer
what we're looking for.
Oh. Sorry.
- How did I do otherwise?
- Oh, good.
- Hey, Cho.
- Yeah.
I think O'Laughlin flaked
on Van Pelt yesterday.
What do you mean?
Well, he saw she was in trouble
and he didn't do anything.
- Guess he was scared.
- It happens.
Yeah.
- Van Pelt doesn't know this?
- No.
I don't know.
The question is,
does she need to know?
Yeah, it's tough.
Your call.
Dr. Steiner, I'm the coroner.
You saw the news story on Hartley's body?
Well, I lied. I did find the body.
There is evidence on it
and it will convict you of murder.
But I haven't given
the police the body.
I've kept it, and I'm willing to sell it
along with my silence, for $50,000.
Because I'm a dying man.
All I want is a few days of real comfort
before I'm gone.
Think about it.
You know how to reach me.
How was that?
Not bad.
Little over-the-top
but, you know, credible, nonetheless.
Sorry.
- Still getting used to all this deception.
- What deception?
You did find Hartley's body
at a funeral home.
Yes, but there was no blood
evidence on it.
You can't catch a fish without bait.
We will tell agent Lisbon
what's going on, yes?
- Oh, yeah, eventually.
- Agent Lisbon's a good person.
She reminds me of...
never mind.
Showtime. Huh?
Let's go.
Yes?
Testing one, two.
Testing two.
"Testing one, two."
Yes, Dr. Steiner.
We can hear you, just like before.
I'm a little nervous.
"You're doing a great job.
You look the part."
Are you sure about this?
Are you ever gonna tire
of asking me that?
No.
Someone's coming.
Go.
- Dr. Steiner?
- Put your hands where I can see 'em!
- Hands! Hands in the air!
- I'm not armed.
I'm... I'm not armed.
I'm not armed.
It's the butler! It's the butler!
It's the butler!
It's the but... the butler did it!
I always wanted to say that.
But wait. It gets better.
Let's go.
Ms. Cook. Good evening. Remember
me? I can't hear anything with this.
The good doctor here told us
that Timothy Hartley's murder
cut himself whilst doing the killing.
Yeah. Would you mind terribly
showing me your hand?
You must let Harrison go.
He has done nothing but serve me
faithfully and well.
As I explained, ma'am our D.A. will
drop the charges against your Butler
if you answer our questions honestly.
I feel like I'm haggling in a
bazaar over the cost of a rug.
But if you will release
Harrison, then I will speak.
Your son-in-law was about to go public
with the whole alien adventure
thing, wasn't he?
More than that.
He wanted to start a global foundation
for abductees
to see to their needs
and promote their cause.
He was gonna call it
The Cook Family Foundation.
Well, that wasn't going to happen.
No, no, no you cannot do this.
- I won't allow it.
- It's not something you can stop.
Try me. I am not without
resources, young man.
"But he said he was gonna use
his own money for it."
- "And then he said..."
- Time's on my side, Elspeth.
What do you mean, Timothy?!
Timothy, come back here!
I knew what he meant.
Hartley was going to wait until I was dead,
and then use my money
and my daughter to turn the Cook name
into an international joke.
So the next time he went to that place
he was always visiting
we followed.
- Why slit Hartley's throat?
- That was the telltale sign...
A hunter's humanity, if you will.
You learned how to hunt and kill
at a young age didn't you, Elspeth?
Your father taught you.
Yes. He was very firm on that point.
"Never let the animal suffer."
I got awfully cross with Consuela
for mislaying this.
I shall have to apologize.
Hey. What's up?
There's something I have to
talk to you about.
What's that?
Wayne?
What is it?
A friend of mine is a ranger
at Vandermeer State Park
and maybe I can get him to give
you a waiver to get married
- at that Quaker meeting house.
- Really?
Yeah. I think. I can try.
Wayne, that's fantastic.
- Thank you so much.
- Yeah.
- I'm gonna call Craig.
- Yeah, okay.
Please.
- Thank you for coming by.
- Oh, it's no problem.
Nice place. Tidy.
Thank you.
Please.
I wanted to tell you
how much I appreciated
your letting me come along
on your investigation.
It was fun.
Hmm, it was fun, wasn't it?
That was my pleasure.
- Thank you.
- Um, look...
Won't beat around the bush.
About me dying...
I-I know what's going to happen now.
I've seen it.
There are no mysteries.
It's going to get bad...
very soon
and then worse.
And I have no interest
in letting nature take its course.
- You understand?
- Uh, yes.
- You, uh, you wanna kill yourself.
- In a nutshell.
I have pills I can take.
The problem is
if there is an unexplained death
if a body is found in an apartment
there is an investigation, an autopsy.
And the idea of being examined
of being a body on the...
on the table...
but if the death is witnessed
by a law enforcement officer
no investigation is required.
I'm not a law enforcement officer.
You're close enough, I think.
I, I don't know that I can do it,
that I can witness that. I...
I'm not even sure that killing
yourself is the best idea.
It's what I'm going to do.
Well, that's your choice.
But, uh...
I understand. I...
I'm sorry.
This was a t...
Terrible imposition.
I-I shouldn't have.
Please.
Forget I said anything.
I'm sorry.
Do you have any tea?
Yes, I do.
I could really use a cup of tea.
Okay.
Sure.
- There's cookies in the cupboard.
- Yeah.
Uh, would you like a cup?
Thank you. Yeah.
Well, uh, I'm going in
the other room now.
- I'll be a few minutes.
- Yeah. Take your time.
Here.
The note in the
dead man's... pocket...
You... you had an arrangement
with the deputy, didn't you?
Yes, I did.
- I knew it.
- Yeah.
It's an old carny magic trick.
- You did magic?
- Oh, yeah.
I first started out, uh, working close-up
with, uh, cards and coins.
- Really?
- Yeah. I'll show you.
Got a coin in here.
Yeah. Okay.
See that coin?
It's there, right?
And it's gone.
It's there...
Then it's gone.
- Amazing.
- It's really quite simple.
It's there...
And then it's gone.
Patrick...
Thank you.
Just watch the coin.
And it's gone.
It's there...
And then it's gone.